Surendra Vikram Singh

User Interface Developer

% http://svsdesigns.in

**** 7774008187

ABOUT

A self-taught UI Developer with 6 Yrs of experience in developing bug-free, performance optimized & responsive web applications with pixel-perfect integration. Recently worked on Facebook, Behance & 500px API and integrated them with AngularJS. I'm looking for a company working on Cutting-edge technologies & focused on quality, where I can develop and implement my knowledge

SKILLS

HTML & CSS

Proficient

Javascript

Intermediate

Adobe Photoshop

Intermediate

Adobe Illustrator

Intermediate

EDUCATION

Diploma In Web Designing

TGC, New Delhi- 2008-2009

B.E In Electrical & Electronics

CSIT, Bhilai- 2003-2007

ON THE WEB

https://dribbble.com/svsdesigns

Bē https://www.behance.net/svsdesigns

http://stackoverFlow.com/users/1160568/svs

in http://in.linkedin.com/in/svsdesigns

EXPERIENCE

Synechron / Sr. Associate - Software April 2013 - September 2014

Developed complex, cross-browser compatible and responsive websites using SASS, Grunt and custom Boilerplate for code maintenance and seamless workflow. Worked on projects like Alcatel-lucent, SABMiller, Sainsbury, NATS, UAE PMO, MSL Group UK & 24/7 Real Media.

Fabulloso / UI Designer/Developer

December 2011 - April 2013

Designed, developed and implemented themes for Magento & Wordpress. Keeping user-centric designs in mind developed interactive features & easy to use interfaces using the latest web technologies and various UX techniques. Optimized the code for better performance and cross-browser compatibilities. Websites showcased by ELLE & The Hindu.

Knowlarity Communication / UI Designer

September 2010 - December 2011

Responsible for front-end design & development of complex web based applications in coordination with developers.

Developed templates using the latest technologies (HTML5, CSS3 & jQuery). Designed Android User interface for one of the major Government projects.

Digisoft Pvt. Ltd. / Web Designer

January 2009 - August 2010

Worked independently on designing and developing static websites. Worked with clients like Jaypee Cement, Flex Foods & many more reputed companies. Also worked on Joomla template customization & Search Engine Optimization.